<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Actually Obvious</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://danekja.github.io/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io" />
<updated>2015-04-08T13:11:02+02:00</updated>
<id>http://danekja.github.io/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jakub Danek</name>
  <uri>http://danekja.github.io/</uri>
  <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Merge 2015 in Paris - Day 0]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io/blog/gitmerge-day-0/" />
  <id>http://danekja.github.io/blog/gitmerge-day-0</id>
  <published>2015-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jakub Danek</name>
    <uri>http://danekja.github.io</uri>
    <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;My stay in Paris started optimistic. At the RER train station of Charles de Gaulle Airport I wanted to buy Navigo Decouvert
 ticket card (similar to e.g. London Oyster). My conversation with the clerk at the desk was rather swift:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She: Bonjour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Me: Bon-jour par-le-vu in-gle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She: No.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She actually didn’t even look at me once. When the lady noticed I didn’t leave, she made an angry gesture to the screen above.
Quick exploration revealed one other clerk had a Brittish flag on his screen. A-ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the guy was friendly, we wished each other nice day and I was leaving with my brand new public transport card. The 
sun was shining, what could go wrong on such a wonderful day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-where-is-this-place-im-stayin&quot;&gt;So, where is this place I’m stayin?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to arrive to Paris one day earlier to the Git Merge 2015 event. I’ve never been to France, so I wanted to have 
enough time in case anything went differently to my expectations. Well, lucky me…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my arrival to the presumed B&amp;amp;B location, I found out it is an appartment building with no visible sings of the 
accomodation service. Quick call to the number provided at the booking took me through a brief automated call receiver
to an english-speaking (yes!) lady. After brief conversation it was obvious there was something wrong with my reservation (damn!). Apparently
it has been cancelled due to invalid credit card and the room is not free anymore. I admit I was a little stunned at that
very moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently don’t know why my credit card wasn’t accepted during the booking (I’ve just paid my new accomodation
without any problems), but that wasn’t the most upsetting issue. What I can’t really grasp is how the hell could my
reservation be cancelled without me getting a single email? Until this very moment my &lt;a href=&quot;www.hotels.com&quot;&gt;Hotels.com&lt;/a&gt; account
claims the reservation to be active and ok!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed a little odd that my account wasn’t charged at the time of the booking, but then there was this sentence present at the 
booking details:&lt;code&gt;You&#39;ll be charged by the hotel in the local currency after your arrival.&lt;/code&gt; There was no e-mail address for the B&amp;amp;B,
 only French phone number, so I let it go. I paid for it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-directions&quot;&gt;New directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s fair to say the lady tried to help me and offered another room at a different location. Unfortunately, our call
 had repeatedly suffered from technical problems and in the end it was impossible to finish the conversation. So I was on
 my own. The task was clear - find a replacement, reasonably distant from the centre and pay less than my
 monthly sallary. I bless the providence which made me buy a roaming mobile data package before my departure as the internet
 connection made things much easier. It took me about two hours to find a new place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am - at a hotel 120 EUR more expensive, without breakfast and wireless (actually, they are both provided at extra
  fees which are ridiculously high). The room is clean, but as the building and equipment are very old, the air is rather stiff. Still,
 I’m very happy to be here. The location is good, the staff is nice and it is warm inside :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest of the day was a pleasant thing. Paris is a beautiful city, the food is awesome (that will take another post, I guess)
 and I had a wonderful walk with my camera. And hell, some of their metro lines are trains with tires!                      &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I can’t wait for the tomorrows start of the Git Merge 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io/blog/gitmerge-day-0/&quot;&gt;Git Merge 2015 in Paris - Day 0&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jakub Danek at &lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io&quot;&gt;Actually Obvious&lt;/a&gt; on April 07, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postmodern Jukebox Tour]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io/blog/pmjtour-prague/" />
  <id>http://danekja.github.io/blog/pmjtour-prague</id>
  <published>2015-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jakub Danek</name>
    <uri>http://danekja.github.io</uri>
    <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When I first ran into Scott Bradlee and his PMJ, I was thrilled with the talent of the musicians and true beauty of their work.
When I introduced PMJ to my father, he was thrilled with the talent of the musicians and true beauty of their work. So, it
was an easy choice to get tickets for their show in Prague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;real-music-is-still-alive-baby&quot;&gt;Real music is still alive, baby!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (the audience) were the proof of that. Mykal Kilgore told us, and considering his performance, he knows a thing or two about music.
Well, all of us got we came for, and much more. Two moments in particular won the night for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First was Scott Bradlee’s improvisation. Given four names of bands or singers by the audience, he just started to improvise
 on their well known songs in the style we are used to hear from PMJ. To me, this moment proved geniality of the man once again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second moment, my personal winner of the night, happened during the late part of the show. Each of the performers had been summoned 
to do a short jam of their own. All of them had amused the audience in their own way, and all of them got well deserved applause.
Yet there was one which, in my eyes, got a little further. &lt;strong&gt;Because one simply does not expect to hear Mozart at this kind of show.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the evening Morgan James had shown us the quality of her voice, yet this was unexpected and simply astonishing. I wish
there was a better record somewhere out there, but well, the one below will have to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/0WOLoxteZf/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Tonight&amp;#39;s curtain call: a little &amp;#34;queen of the night&amp;#34; :) #pmjtour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;Video zveřejněné uživatelem Morgan James (@morganajames), &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-03-17T23:26:44+00:00&quot;&gt;Bře 17, 2015 v 4:26 PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we got a bit more than just music…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-too-fabulous-for-only-one-husband&quot;&gt;You are too fabulous for only one husband&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a change, Ariana Savalas’ piece of advice for a girl of her own age (19, as we all heard and seen). Pretty much covers 
the other great trait of the evening. All the concerts I’ve seen up to date tried to combine music and show. Most managed one thing
better than the other, I’ve heard some even fail in both (don’t go to these thougn). Well PMJ provided us with both. When I saw Ian Anderson in Pilsen couple years
ago, well, that was a great performance. To this very day I don’t understand how he manages
to play his flute whilst moving around the stage the way he does. His performance was for a long time the best thing I’ve had a chance
to see. Up until yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PMJ did great job working with the audience. Intermezzos between the songs were commonly filled with laughter. It did not really 
matter whether it was Mykal Kilgore ostentatiously presenting his self-confidence or Ariana Savalas flirting with the two well-dressed 
gentlemen in the audience femme-fatale style. Chapter of its own was Casey Abrams, who, just like Ian Anderson, makes one wonder
how the hell can he play and sing while jumping like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altogether the whole group, including those not mentioned namely here, managed to make the audience feel welcome and important. We all certainly hope you are 
all coming back to Prague soon. ‘Cause you are too fabulous for not coming back. ‘Cause we are all about that bass…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aLnZ1NQm2uk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: No pictures today, because I’m the moron who forgot his camera at home and cellphone didn’t cope with the conditions 
 (surprise, surprise).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io/blog/pmjtour-prague/&quot;&gt;Postmodern Jukebox Tour&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jakub Danek at &lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io&quot;&gt;Actually Obvious&lt;/a&gt; on March 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yet Another Helsinki Trip]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io/blog/helsinki-again/" />
  <id>http://danekja.github.io/blog/helsinki-again</id>
  <published>2015-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jakub Danek</name>
    <uri>http://danekja.github.io</uri>
    <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;One would think that after spending so much time in Helsinki, there is not too much to be discovered. Well, I’ve been
proven wrong once again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;need-a-place-to-crash&quot;&gt;Need a place to crash?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a notorious fact that hotels and accommodation services in general are awfully expensive
in Finland (comparing to mid-european countries or even Austria and Germany). What was my surprise when
I learned from my contractor that my apartment costs only about 40 EUR / night and, that is the best part, it is
only 5 minutes walk from Kamppi (central bus station located in the middle of the city). Sounds too good to be true, hey?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, as many other things in Finland, such miracles actually do exist and they usually are as good as they seem to be. I’ve just
realized I haven’t taken any pictures of the apartment, so the plain old description will have to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citykoti.com&quot;&gt;TL;DR: it’s awesome, I can recommend it to fellow travellers. Check them out!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The apartment consisted of a tiny entry hall (about 1 - 2 square meters), tiny bathroom (about 4 square meters) and
one regular room, which could’ve been about 16 square meters. These tiny apartments are nothing unusual in Finland, yet
this one was the first I’ve considered actually comfy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The place had everything - cooker, refrigerator, coffee machine, dishwasher. Enough space to prepare and eat meals. 
Large double bed. TV, wireless. Washing machine in the bathroom….&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Altogether, the apartment is just fine for a single traveller or a couple which returns only to spend the night. I 
can imagine that over a longer period of time the lack of proper “workspace” might become annoying and in case of a couple,
 the lack of privacy could become rather frustrating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;those-tiny-moments&quot;&gt;Those tiny moments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As any other place in the World, Helsinki have their moments of beauty. I had been lucky enough to catch a few of those during this
stay - spring is obviously coming to Finland. Even if the sunny boulevards weren’t enough, the street artist performing
Antonio Vivaldi’s Four Seasons (guess which parts in particular) was definitely the most welcome proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.zonerama.com/Embed/Album/587555?color=gray-dark&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;vertical=false&quot; style=&quot;width: 720px; height: 330px;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, as a very close friend told me recently - “All the things must come to an end” - hence I took my departure to Vantaa
airport and left the country once again.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io/blog/helsinki-again/&quot;&gt;Yet Another Helsinki Trip&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jakub Danek at &lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io&quot;&gt;Actually Obvious&lt;/a&gt; on March 15, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>