<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Actually Obvious</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://danekja.github.io//feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io/" />
<updated>2015-03-16T22:33:22+01:00</updated>
<id>http://danekja.github.io//</id>
<author>
  <name>Jakub Danek</name>
  <uri>http://danekja.github.io//</uri>
  <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yet Another Helsinki Trip]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://danekja.github.io//blog/helsinki-again/" />
  <id>http://danekja.github.io//blog/helsinki-again</id>
  <published>2015-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jakub Danek</name>
    <uri>http://danekja.github.io/</uri>
    <email>danek.ja@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;One would think that after spending so much time in Helsinki, there is not too much to be discovered. Well, I’ve been
proven wrong once again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;need-a-place-to-crash&quot;&gt;Need a place to crash?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a notorious fact that hotels and accommodation services in general are awfully expensive
in Finland (comparing to mid-european countries or even Austria and Germany). What was my surprise when
I learned from my contractor that my apartment costs only about 40 EUR / night and, that is the best part, it is
only 5 minutes walk from Kamppi (central bus station located in the middle of the city). Sounds too good to be true, hey?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, as many other things in Finland, such miracles actually do exist and they usually are as good as they seem to be. I’ve just
realized I haven’t taken any pictures of the apartment, so the plain old description will have to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citykoti.com&quot;&gt;TL;DR: it’s awesome, I can recommend it to fellow travellers. Check them out!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The apartment consisted of a tiny entry hall (about 1 - 2 square meters), tiny bathroom (about 4 square meters) and
one regular room, which could’ve been about 16 square meters. These tiny apartments are nothing unusual in Finland, yet
this one was the first I’ve considered actually comfy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The place had everything - cooker, refrigerator, coffee machine, dishwasher. Enough space to prepare and eat meals. 
Large double bed. TV, wireless… Washing machine in the bathroom….&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Altogether, the apartment is just fine for a single person or a couple which returns there only to spend the night. I 
can imagine that over a longer period of time the lack of proper “workspace” would become annoying and in case of two
people living together, also the lack of privacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;those-tiny-moments&quot;&gt;Those tiny moments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As any other place in the World, Helsinki have their moments of beauty. I had been lucky enough to catch a few of those during this
stay - spring is obviously coming to Finland. Even if the sunny boulevards weren’t enough, the street artist performing
Antonio Vivaldi’s Four Seasons (guess which parts in particular) was definitely the most welcome proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.zonerama.com/Embed/Album/587555?color=gray-dark&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;vertical=false&quot; style=&quot;width: 720px; height: 330px;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, as a very close friend told me recently - “All the things must come to an end” - hence I took my departure to Vantaa
airport and left the country once again.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io//blog/helsinki-again/&quot;&gt;Yet Another Helsinki Trip&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jakub Danek at &lt;a href=&quot;http://danekja.github.io/&quot;&gt;Actually Obvious&lt;/a&gt; on March 15, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>